GEOFFREY MAHLEY

1525 Edith Street, Berkeley, CA 94703

P. (510) 206-8652 E. gemahley@ucdavis.edu

PROFILE
Soon to be UC Davis Graduate with a B.S. in Environmental Policy Analysis and Planning (focus in Water Resource Management) seeking work experience in water policy. Spent two years assembling/constructing membrane modules that used AroNite technology to treat water polluted with nitrates. Volunteer for Youth and Government program that teaches high schoolers state government procedures and helps students build public speaking and leadership skills. Co-founder of Blood and Bolts Apparel.
EDUCATION
Bachelors of Science in Environmental Policy Analysis and Planning (focus in Water Resource Management) University of California Davis, Degree expected June 2015, Current GPA 3.36
RELEVANT COURSEWORK
WATER LAW - Learned principles and issues of California Water Law, types of water rights, groundwater rights and management, and protection of instream uses. Water projects, role of federal government and federal/state relations.
WATER POLICY AND POLITICS - Examined the rules governing how water is used, the politics of water decision-making, and whether or not the rules are effective at providing clean water for human consumption and ecosystem maintenance.
GEOGRAPHICAL INFORMATION SYSTEMS - Two classes focused on the creation of spatial data sets from analog and digital sources such as aerial photography and maps; data structures, data management, database design, georeferencing, georectification, surface models, analysis, and spatial data visualization.
HYDROLOGIC PROCESSES OF ECOSYSTEMS - Hydrological processes in individual ecosystems and the role of water linking the myriad components of the landscape.
ENVIRONMENTAL LAW - Highlights of most pertinent environmental legislation and briefing of historic environmental cases.
ENVIRONMENT IMPACT ASSESSMENT - Principles, methods of analysis and decision-making used in CEQA and NEPA documents
ENVIRONMENTAL POLICY ANALYSIS - Evaluation of alternatives for solution of complex environmental problems; impact analysis, benefitcost analysis, distributional analysis, decision making under uncertainty, and multi-objective evaluation.
PRINCIPALS OF ENVIRONMENTAL SCIENCE - Application of physical and chemical principles, ecological concepts, and systems approach to policy analysis.
SKILLS
ArcGIS / QGIS / Microsoft Excel / Microsoft Word / Microsoft Powerpoint / Extensive knowledge of power tools / Excellent collaborator / Great at facilitating discussions.
WORK EXPERIENCE
CALIFORNIA YMCA YOUTH AND GOVERNMENT – Berkeley, CA - Advisor, August 2012 to Present Help high school aged youths develop personal and public speaking skills, research capabilities when drafting mock legislation, leadership qualities, fundraising development, and networking skills through active program participation. Contributed to three straight

BLOOD AND BOLTS APPAREL - Marketing/Sales Director and Head of Outreach, January 2013 to Present Contact prospective buyers, develop and maintain relationships with current and former buyers, brainstorm/implement marketing strategies.

CAMERON PROCESS SYSTEMS – Pittsburg, CA - Assembly and Carpentry, June 2012 to October 2014 Assembled membrane modules that cleaned nitrate polluted water using AroNite technology. Oversaw performance tests on the membrane modules and the water produced. Performed diverse carpentry tasks to improve efficiency throughout the shop.